Finding Aid for the Roger Mennevée collection of research material relating to French political, social, economic, and artistic life, 1910-1965. LSC.899
UCLA Library Special Collections
Roger Mennevée collection of research material relating to French political, social, economic, and artistic life
ca. 1910-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.899
1221.5 linear feet 2443 boxes, 9 cartons, and 58 oversize boxes
Roger Mennevée was a researcher, journalist, editor and publisher of a private newsletter: Les Documents Politiques, Diplomatiques et Financiers. The archive was assembled by Mr. Mennevée from the more than 50 years of extensive research in the preparation of his newsletter. The majority of the collection was obtained in 1965, while the rest was donated in 1969, on the occasion of Mennevée's retirement. As a collection of research items, the Mennevée archive is an exhaustive mine of information which documents social, political, economic and artistic life in France between 1910 and 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roger Mennevée 1965 and 1969.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942334073606533
Administrative/Biographical History
Roger Mennevée was a researcher, journalist, editor and publisher of a private newsletter: Les Documents Politiques, Diplomatiques et Financiers. Les Documents was widely considered, in academic circles, to be one of the best informed newsletters of its kind. The archive was assembled by Mr. Mennevée from the more than 50 years of extensive research in the preparation of his newsletter. The majority of the collection was obtained in 1965, while the rest was donated in 1969, on the occasion of Mennevée's retirement.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains material related to Menevée's career as editor and publisher of Les informations politiques et financières and Les documents politiques, diplomatiques, et financiers. Includes clippings, correspondence, periodicals, pamphlets, broadsheets, government publications, and bulletins. Mennevée developed an extensive collection of biographical and subject files which provided the resources for his research and publications. The bulk of the files concern political, economic, and diplomatic life between 1914 and 1940 collected from French and foreign presses, the Stock Exchange, financial companies, and official announcements.
Arrangement
The Roger Mennevee's original organization of the collection has been maintained. Mennevee collected and maintained files on a huge array of topics, which were categorized into the following 9 series:
1) Archive of Contemporary Biography 2) Press Archive 3) Espionage and Secret Service Archive 4) Secret Societies and Occultism 5) Political Archive 6) Economic and Financial Archive 7) Loose Folders and Additions 8) Catalogs, Listings and Indices 9) Documentation Générale
- 1. Archive of contemporary biography
  - Files numbered 15,000-21,669
    - Rothschild Family (Box 1)
    - Rothschild Family -- generalities (Box 2)
    - Rothschild Family -- international affairs (Box 3)
    - Rothschild -- foreign branches (Box 4)
      Scope and Contents
      Contains files on the German, Austrian, American, Italian, and Belgian Branches of the Rothschild Family
    - Rothschild Family -- London (Box 5)
      Contains files on the London-based Rothschild family business including notes of birth and death dates including newspaper clippings
    - Rothschild Family -- French 1, 1809-1851 (Box 6)
      Contains files on the France-based Rothschild family business, historic dossier
    - Rothschild Family -- French 2, 1851-1918 (Box 7)
      Contains files on the France-based Rothschild family business, historic dossier 2
    - Rothschild Family -- French 3, 1919-1940 (Box 8)
      Contains files on the France-based Rothschild family business during the 3rd Republic, historic dossier 3
    - Rothschild Family -- French personalities - 1 (Box 9)
      Contains files regarding personality sketches of the France-based Rothschild family
    - Rothschild Family -- French personalities - 2 (Box 10, Box 11)
    - Rothschild Family -- French personalities - 3 (Box 12)
    - Le banque de Rothschild Frères (Box 13)
    - La banque de Rothschild Filiales Diverses, 1945-1965 (Box 14)
    - Rothschild Compagnie Financière-Edmond de Rothschild (Box 15)
    - Rothschild Ouvrages Divers (Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19)
      Collected books regarding the Rothschilds
    - Biographie contemporaine (Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66, Box 67, Box 68, Box 69, Box 70, Box 71, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74, Box 75, Box 76, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79, Box 80, Box 81, Box 82, Box 83, Box 84, Box 85, Box 86, Box 87, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94, Box 95, Box 96, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114, Box 115, Box 116, Box 117, Box 118, Box 119, Box 120, Box 121, Box 122, Box 123, Box 124, Box 125, Box 126, Box 127, Box 128, Box 129, Box 130, Box 131, Box 132, Box 133, Box 134, Box 135, Box 136, Box 137, Box 138, Box 139, Box 140, Box 141, Box 142, Box 143, Box 144, Box 145, Box 146, Box 147, Box 148, Box 149, Box 150, Box 151, Box 152, Box 153, Box 154, Box 155, Box 156, Box 157, Box 158, Box 159, Box 160, Box 161, Box 162, Box 163, Box 164, Box 165, Box 166, Box 167, Box 168, Box 169, Box 170, Box 171, Box 172, Box 173, Box 174, Box 175, Box 176, Box 177, Box 178, Box 179, Box 180, Box 181, Box 182, Box 183, Box 184, Box 185, Box 186, Box 187, Box 188, Box 189, Box 190, Box 191, Box 192, Box 193, Box 194, Box 195, Box 196, Box 197, Box 198, Box 199, Box 200, Box 201, Box 202, Box 203, Box 204, Box 205, Box 206, Box 207, Box 208, Box 209, Box 210, Box 211, Box 212, Box 213, Box 214, Box 215, Box 216, Box 217, Box 218, Box 219, Box 220, Box 221, Box 222, Box 223, Box 224, Box 225, Box 226, Box 227, Box 228, Box 229, Box 230, Box 231, Box 232, Box 233, Box 234, Box 235, Box 236, Box 237, Box 238, Box 239, Box 240, Box 245, Box 246, Box 247, Box 248, Box 249, Box 250, Box 251, Box 252, Box 253, Box 254, Box 255, Box 256, Box 257, Box 258, Box 259, Box 260, Box 261, Box 262, Box 263, Box 264, Box 265, Box 266, Box 267, Box 268, Box 269, Box 270, Box 271, Box 272, Box 273, Box 274, Box 275, Box 276, Box 277, Box 278, Box 279, Box 280, Box 281, Box 282, Box 283, Box 284, Box 285, Box 286, Box 287, Box 288, Box 289, Box 290, Box 291, Box 292, Box 293, Box 294, Box 295, Box 296, Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 300, Box 301, Box 302, Box 303, Box 304, Box 305, Box 306, Box 307, Box 308, Box 309, Box 310, Box 311, Box 312, Box 313, Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 317, Box 318, Box 319, Box 320, Box 321, Box 322, Box 323, Box 324, Box 325, Box 326, Box 327, Box 328, Box 329, Box 330, Box 331, Box 332, Box 333, Box 334, Box 335, Box 336, Box 337, Box 338, Box 339, Box 340, Box 341, Box 342, Box 343, Box 344, Box 345, Box 346, Box 347, Box 348, Box 349, Box 350, Box 351, Box 352, Box 353, Box 354, Box 355, Box 356, Box 357, Box 358, Box 359, Box 360, Box 361, Box 362, Box 363, Box 364, Box 365, Box 366, Box 367, Box 368, Box 369, Box 370, Box 371, Box 372, Box 373, Box 374, Box 375, Box 376, Box 377, Box 378, Box 379, Box 380, Box 381, Box 382, Box 383, Box 384, Box 385, Box 386, Box 387, Box 388, Box 389, Box 390, Box 391, Box 392, Box 393, Box 394)
  - Files à classer A-Z
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. A (Box 395)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. B - 1 (Box 396)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. B - 2 (Box 397)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. C - 1 (Box 398)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. C - 2 (Box 399)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. D (Box 400)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer (Box 401)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. G (Box 402)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. H (Box 403)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. J et K (Box 404)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. L (Box 405)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. M - 1 (Box 406)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. M - 2 (Box 407)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. N et O (Box 408)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. P (Box 409)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. Q et R (Box 410)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. S - 1 (Box 411)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. S - 2 (Box 412)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. A classer. T et U (Box 413)
  - Notes et documents divers
    - Documents de Biographie Contemporaine. A classer V à Z / Notes et documents divers, 1946-1947 (Box 414, Box 415)
  - Files marked Personalités
    - Biographie Contemporaine. Personnalités P - 1. P - 2 (Box 416, Box 417)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. Personnalités P - 3. P - 4 (Box 418, Box 419)
  - Archives Financières - Personalités
    - Personnalités - 1 (Box 420)
    - Personnalités - 2 (Box 421)
    - Personnalités - 3 (Box 422)
  - Dossiers Complémentaires: A
    - Biographie Historique A - G (Box 423)
    - Biographie Historique H - Q (Box 424)
    - Biographie Historique R - Z et A Classer (Box 425)
  - Dossiers Complémentaires: B
    - Brochures Biographique (Box 426)
  - Dossiers Complémentaires: C-E
    - Documents de Biographie: Financiers du XVIII Siècle (Box 427)
  - Poincaré
    - Poincaré (Box 428, Box 429, Box 430, Box 431, Box 432, Box 433, Box 434, Box 435, Box 436, Box 437)
  - Les Mallet
    - Mallet Frères (Box 438, Box 439, Box 440, Box 441, Box 442, Box 443, Box 444)
    - Mallet Frères et Cie 37 rue d'Anjou à Paris VIII Grande Banque Protestante (Box 445)
  - Répertoire (Louis) Launay. Mes Dossiers, Dictionnaire Biographique Francais Contemporain (Pharos), Dictionnaire des Contemporains
    - Répertoire Launay 446. Biogr. Contemporaine 447/2 Le Crapouillot. Dictionnaire des Contemporains. 1950 447/3 (Box 446, Box 447)
  - Etat Civil: Naissances, mariages, décès d'après le Carnet mondain du Figaro
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Juillet-Décembre 1958 (Box 448)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Janvier-Décembre 1954 (Box 449, Box 450)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Janvier-Décembre 1955 (Box 451, Box 452)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Janvier-Juin 1956 (Box 453)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Juillet-Décembre 1956 (Box 454)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Janvier-Juin 1957 (Box 455)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Juillet-Décembre 1957 (Box 456)
    - ETATS-CIVIL/Naissance Mariages - Décès /d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro Janvier-Juin 1958 (Box 457)
    - Etat-Civil Naissances Mariages - Décès d'après le Carnet Mondain du Figaro 1958 Juillet-Décembre (Box 458)
  - Additions October 1971
    - Biographie Contemporaine 1 Personnalités/ A--B (Box 2131)
    - Biographie Contemporaine 2 Personnalités/ C--D (Box 2132)
    - Biographie Contemporaine 3 Personnalités/ E--G (Box 2133)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Personnalités/ H - L (Box 2134)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Personnalités/ M - F (Box 2135)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Personnalités/ R - S (Box 2136)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Personnalités/ T - Z (Box 2137)
    - Biographie Contemporaine de Balkany [Zellinger dit] Personnalités Coston Henry. Lectures Francaises. Personnalités (Box 2138-39)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Dassault Marcel et son Groupe d'Affaires. De Gaulle -1- avant 1965 Personnalités. (Box 2140-41)
    - Biographie Contemporaine De Gaulle -2- 1965-Avril 1967. Personnalités. (Box 2142)
    - Biographie Contemporaine De Gaulle -3- Mai 1967 à Fin 1969 Delterre Gaston. Personnalités (Box 2143-44)
    - Biographie Contemporaine -Deterding Henry. -Monnet Jean. -Onassis et Jacqueline ex Kennedy. Personnalités. (Box 2145-47)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. -Pompidou. -Rolland Romain. Personnalités. (Box 2148-49)
    - Biographie Contemporaine. -Thant U. Secrétaire Général de l'O.N.U. -Vivion Pierre. -Banques Privées Etrangères Personnalités (Box 2150-52)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises (Box 2153)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Les Rothschild -1- Histoire Générale (Box 2154)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Les Rothschild -2- Branches Francaises (Box 2155)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Les Rothschild -3- Banques de Rothschild Frères 1810-1967 (Box 2156)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Les Rothschild -3bis 1960 Banque Rothschild (Box 2157)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Les Rothschild -4- 2e Branche Francaise La Compagnie Financière (Box 2158)
    - Rothschild (Box 2159)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises Lazard Frères et Cie Banques Privées Francaises Louis Dreyfus (Box 2160-61)
    - Biographie Contemporaine Banques Privées Francaises -De Neuftize Schlamberger Mallet et Cie. -Worms et Cie. (Le Groupe) (Box 2162-63)
- 2. Press archive, 1910-1960
  - 10001 - 10005 (Box 459)
  - 10006 - 100013 (Box 460)
  - 10007 Le Bonnet Rouge. 1. Collection 1913 - 1917 (Box 461)
  - 10007 Le Bonnet Rouge. 2. L'Affaire de "Trahison" (Box 462)
  - 10007 Le Bonnet Rouge. 3. Editions d'Après Guerre (Box 463)
  - Press Archive (Box 464, Box 472, Box 473, Box 475, Box 526, Box 527, Box 555)
  - 10012 La Liberté (Box 465)
  - 10014 - 10024 (Box 466)
  - 10025 - 10028 (Box 467)
  - 10029 Agence Havas. (Box 468)
  - 10030 - 10038 (Box 469)
  - 10031 Le Figaro (Box 470)
  - 10033 Librairie Hachette (Box 471)
  - 10057 Le Journal (Box 474)
  - 10071 - 10081 (Box 476)
  - 10077 L'Internationale (Box 477)
  - 10082 - 10099 (Box 478)
  - 10090 L'Ere Nouvelle - 1 (Box 479)
  - 10090 L'Ere Nouvelle - 2 (Box 480)
  - 10094 Le Progrès Civique - Le Quotidien (Box 481)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - 1 (Box 482)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - 2 - 3 (Box 483, Box 484)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - 4 (Box 485)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - 4bis (Box 486)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - Juin à Septembre 1940. 5 (Box 487)
  - 10100 - Le Matin - Octobre à Décembre 1940. 6 (Box 488)
  - 10101 - 10124 (Box 489)
  - 10115 Action Française - 1 (Box 490)
  - 10115 Action Française - 2 (Box 491)
  - 10125 Petit Parisien (Box 492)
  - 10126 - 10137 (Box 493)
  - 10138 -10150 (Box 494)
  - 10151-10165 (Box 495)
  - 10166-10190 (Box 496)
  - 10191-10199 (Box 497)
  - 10200-10210 (Box 498)
  - 10211-10288 (Box 499)
  - A,B (Box 499/A)
  - B (Box 499/B, Box 499/C, Box 499/D)
  - B,C (Box 499/E, Box 499/F)
  - C,D (Box 499/G)
  - D,E,F (Box 499/H)
  - F,G (Box 499/I)
  - G,H (Box 499/J)
  - I,J,K,L (Box 499/K)
  - L (Box 499/L)
  - L,M (Box 499/M)
  - M,N (alphebetized) (Box 499/N)
  - P, Q, R (Box 499/O)
  - R,S (Box 499/P)
  - S, T (Box 499/Q)
  - T, U, V (Box 499/R)
  - W, X, Y, Z (Box 499/S)
  - 10218 Journal des rentiers (Box 500)
  - 10229 - 10249 (Box 501)
  - 10233 Paris - Soir (Box 502)
  - 10244 L'Echo National (Box 503)
  - 10250 - 10263 (Box 504)
  - 10254 Agence Economique et Financière. 1 (Box 505)
  - 10254 Agence Economique et Financière. Actualités. 2 (Box 506)
  - 10264 - 10270 (Box 507)
  - 10271 - 10281 (Box 508)
  - 10282 - 10289 (Box 509)
  - 10300 - 10310 (Box 510)
  - 10311 - 10330 (Box 0511)
  - 10331 - 10356 (Box 512)
  - 10357 - 10380 (Box 513)
  - 10381 - 10410 (Box 514)
  - 10411 - 10425 (Box 515)
  - 10426 - 10440 (Box 516)
  - 10343 Le Cri du Peuple (Box 517)
  - 10441-10450 (Box 518)
  - 10451-10470 (Box 519)
  - 10466 AUJOURD'HUI (Box 520)
  - 10471-10490 (Box 521)
  - 10491-10540 (Box 522)
  - 10541-10570 (Box 523)
  - LA FRANCE AU TRAVAIL 1 (Box 524)
  - LA FRANCE AU TRAVAIL 2 (Box 525)
  - LE MONITEUR DE LA PRESSE. (Box 528)
  - Société des Usines à papiers et Papeteries J.B. Weibel Réunies. (Box 529)
  - 10573-10599 (Box 530)
  - 10600-10630 (Box 531)
  - 10631-10650 (Box 532)
  - 10651-10670 (Box 533)
  - 10768 SIGNAL. (Box 534)
  - 10671-10690 (Box 535)
  - 10691-10735 (Box 536)
  - Gringoire Revue de France. Editions de France (Box 537)
  - La France Libre (de Londres) 1944 - 1945 voir aussi le Dossier 1535 (Box 538)
  - 10728 Notre Temps. Toute la vie (Box 539)
  - 10736 - 10770 (Box 540)
  - 10770 - 10799 (Box 541)
  - 10800 - 10860 (Box 542)
  - 10861 - 10885 (Box 543)
  - 10869 Savez-Vous (Box 544)
  - 10886 - 10910 (Box 545)
  - 10911 - 10960 (Box 546)
  - 10932 Le Canard Enchainé (Box 547)
  - 10931 Le Carnet du Diplomate Inconnu. 1937 - 1938 voir aussi le dossier 10931 (Box 548)
  - 10961 - 10999 (Box 549)
  - 10963 Agence Prior (Box 550)
  - 1001 - 1050 (Box 551)
  - 1051 - 1100 (Box 552)
  - 1059 Le Dernières Nouvelles de Paris (Box 553)
  - 1101 - 1150 (Box 554)
  - Agence Française d'Informations et de Presse. 1. (Box 556)
  - Agence Française d'Informations et de Presse. 2. (Box 557/1)
  - Agence Française d'Informations et de Presse. 2. (Box 0557/2)
  - 1168 - 1199 (Box 558)
  - 1200 - 1254 (Box 559)
  - 1230 Le Soir de Bruxelles (Box 560)
  - 1255 Cahier Jaune (Box 561)
  - 1256 - 1277 (Box 562)
  - 1278 - 1290 (Box 563)
  - 1291 - 1317 (Box 564)
  - France Soir (Box 565)
  - 1319 - 1338 (Box 566)
  - 1329 L'Aurore (Box 567)
  - 1338 Le Monde (Box 568)
  - 1339 - 1358 (Box 569)
  - 1359 - 1390 (Box 570)
  - 1390 - 1399 (Box 571)
  - 1400-1418 (Box 572)
  - 1419-1429 (Box 573)
  - 1430-1450 (Box 574)
  - 1451-1477 (Box 575)
  - 1478-1492 (Box 576)
  - 1493-1517 (Box 577)
  - 1496 LA REVUE INTERNATIONALE 1946 (Box 578)
  - 1518-1543 (Box 579)
  - 1531 GROUPE REALITES (Box 580)
  - 1532 INTER-AVIA (de Genève) 1946 (Box 581)
  - 1544-1564 (Box 582)
  - 1565-1597 (Box 583)
  - 1567 PUBLICIS Groupe Bleustein Dassault (Box 584)
  - 1598-1633 (Box 585)
  - 1613 CHARIVARI 1961-63 (Box 586)
  - 1634-1689 (Box 587)
  - 1690-1723 (Box 588)
  - 1724-1747 (Box 589)
  - 1748 - 1775 (Box 590)
  - 1767 (Box 591)
  - 1776-1799 (Box 592)
  - 1798 Demain 1955 (Box 593)
  - 1800-1827 (Box 594)
  - 1828-1846 (Box 595)
  - Presse A Classer A-B (Box 597)
  - Presse A Classer C-D (Box 598)
  - Presse A Classer E (Box 599)
  - Presse A Classer F, G, H (Box 600)
  - Presse A Classer I, J, L (Box 601)
  - Presse A Classer M (Box 602)
  - Presse A Classer N, O (Box 603)
  - Presse A Classer P (Box 604)
  - Presse A Classer Q, R (Box 605)
  - Presse A Classer S, T, U, V (Box 606)
  - Généralités (Box 607/1&2)
  - Additions Oct. 1971
    - Presse PR 1 A - B (Box 2164)
    - Presse PR 2 C - D (Box 2165)
    - Presse PR 3 E - K (Box 2166)
    - Presse PR 4 L - P (Box 2167)
    - Presse PR 5 R - Z (Box 2168)
    - Presse PR. Groupe Bourgine. Agence Econ. Et Financ. Nouveau Journal. Spectacle du Monde. Valeurs Actuelles. -L'Evènement -1- 1966 Incomplet. (Box 2170-71)
    - -L'Evènement. -2- 1967 Presse. PR Planète (Box 2172-73)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 1 1965. Janvier - Juin (Box 2174)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 2 1965. Juillet - Décembre (Box 2175)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 3 1966. Janvier-Juin (Box 2176)
    - Informations et Conjoncture Juillet-Decembre 1966 -4-. Janvier-Juin 1967 -5-. (Box 2177-78)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 1967 - Juillet-Decembre -6-. 1968 - Janvier-Juin -7-. (Box 2179-80)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 1968 - Juillet-Decembre -8-. (Box 2181)
    - Informations et Conjoncture 1969 -9-. (Box 2182)
    - Presse Le Figaro (Box 2183)
    - Presse Le Monde (Box 2184)
    - Presse Echo de la Presse. -1- Le Chirvari. (Box 2185)
    - Presse Echo de la Presse. -2- 1966 (Box 2186)
    - Presse Echo de la Presse. -3- Nos Divers. (Box 2187)
    - Presse Politique Quotidienne 1939 1er au 10 Septembre. (Box 2188/A)
    - Presse Politique 1 (Box 2188/B)
    - Presse Politique -2- Ive République. Presse. Généralités (Box 2188/C-D)
    - Presse. Généralités. Associations. Législation. -La Presse Francaise sous Pétain et pendant l'Occupation. [Généralités] (Box 2188/F-G)
    - Presse Internationale après la 2e Guerre Mondiale. Généralités. Presse Francaise après Liberation Epuration-Censure-Papier-Restrictions de Tirages. Association Professionelle des Journalistes. (Box 2188/H-J)
    - Ministère de l'Information. Bulletins de Change. De la Journée Industrielle 1938 (Box 2188/K-L)
    - Jurisprudence (Box 2188/M)
    - Revue "FUTUR" Octobre 1965 (No. 1) à Juin 1966. Juillet 1966 à Avril 1967 (fin) (Box 2189/A-B)
- 3. Espionage and secret services
  - Bound Volumes
    - Espionnage 1871-1914 (Box 608)
    - Espionnage 1914-1919 (Box 609)
    - 1914-1919 Etranger 1922-1924 (Box 610-611)
    - 1925-1926, 1927 (Box 612-613)
    - 1928, 1928/2 (Box 614-615)
    - 1929, 1930 (Box 616-617)
    - 1931, 1932 I (Box 618-619)
    - 1932 II (Box 620)
    - 1933 I (Box 621)
    - 1933 II Affaires/Hohelohe/Eydoux Frogé/Causeret-Huot/Igénieurs Anglais/ A Moscou, 1933 III (Box 622-623)
    - 1934 I,II (Box 624-625)
    - 1935 I (Box 626-627)
    - 1935 II Frogé/Dumoulin/Eberlein/Suisse 1935III (Box 628-629)
    - 1936 I, 1936 II (Box 630-631)
    - 1937 I (Box 632)
    - 1937 II (Box 633)
    - 1937 III (Box 634)
    - 1938 I (Box 635)
    - 1938 II, 1938 III (Box 636-637)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1939 I (Box 638)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1939 II (Box 639)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1940 I 1940 II (Box 640-641)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1941, 1942-1943 (Box 642-643)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1944-45 (Box 644)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1946, 1947 (Box 645-646)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1948/1, 1948/2 (Box 647-648)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1949/1 (Box 649)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1950/1 (Box 650)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1951/1 1951/2 (Box 651-652)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1952/1, 1953 (Box 653-654)
    - ESPIONNAGE 1954/1, 1954/2 (Box 655-656)
    - 1955, 1956 (Box 657-658)
    - 1957, 1958 (Box 659-660)
    - 1959 (Box 661)
    - 1960/1, 1960/2 (Box 662-663)
    - 1961/1, 1961/2 (Box 664-665)
    - A Classer 1962/1 (Box 666)
    - A Classer 1962/2 (Box 667)
    - A Classer 1963 (Box 668)
    - A Classer 1964 (Box 669)
    - Guerre de 1914-1918, Documents originaux, Documents Iconographiques de Presse (Box 670)
    - Entre Deux Guerres, Doubles, Plus ou moins complets (Box 671)
    - A Classer En Instance de reliure Compléments aux années 1914-1943 (Box 672)
    - A Classer dans les volumes ou dossiers existants depuis 1944 (Box 673)
    - Généralités (Box 674)
    - A Classer: Généralités (Box 675)
    - Cryptographie I: Généralités (Box 676)
    - Cryptographie 2 (Box 677)
    - Affaires Diverses 1949/3 (Box 678)
    - Affaires Diverses: Espionnage Soviétique 1952/2 (Box 679)
    - Affaires Particulières I, Affaires Particulières 1940-1944 (Box 680-681)
    - Affaires Particulières 1950/2, Affaires Particulières 1951 (Box 682-683)
    - Affaires Particulières 1953 (Box 684)
    - Affaires Particulières 1954 (Box 685)
    - Affaires Particulières I 1955, Affaires Particulières II 1955 (Box 686-687)
    - Affaires Particulières 1956 (Box 688)
    - Grands Espions Modernes (Box 689)
    - Affaire Peyré Généraux I 1950 (Box 690)
    - Affaire Peyré Généraux II 1950, Affaire Peyré Généraux III 1950 (Box 691-692)
    - Affaire Peyré Généraux IV 1950, Affaire Peyré Généraux V 1950 et Passim (Box 693-694)
    - Affaire Peyré Généraux VI Con Pre D'Enquète 1 1950 (Box 695)
    - Affaire Peyré/Généraux/VII/Con Pre/D'Enquète/3/1950 (Box 696-697)